Fady Faheem

9749 Burwell Dr, Fort Worth, TX 76244 (682) 717-6391

contact@fadyfaheem.com - E-Portfolio: fadyfaheem.com

Languages: English & Arabic

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Creative and problem-solving application and frontend engineer with over 5+ *years of delivering high-end software* and frontend engineering services to high-value clients. Strong passion for both developing applications and websites with great user experiences. Currently working on difficult programming problems and learning from real-world challenges. My skills include the following:

- HTML, CSS
- React.JS
- Swift
- C# and Unity

- Java and JavaScript
- Python
- Team Building / Leadership
- Verbal/Written Communications
- Agile/Scrum Management
- **Quick Learner**
- Drives Results
- Team Player

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bell Textron Inc.

Software Engineering Intern

Arlington, TX

September 2022-Present

- Developed and developing apps for both iOS and Android using Swift and Java to reduce loss of time due to insufficient access to proper data.
- Developed backend tools using Firebase, MySQL, and Back4App with web interface solutions using HTML, JavaScript, CSS and React.JS
- Created and maintained a computer management tool for accessing the latest application builds to all necessary devices.
- Work closely with other teams, managing iOS and Android Applications for over 25+ Full Flight **Simulators** with thousands of documents, including keeping up to date and creating a document retention system.

Professional Development

Fort Worth, TX

May 2022-September 2022

- Worked on developing my professional communication and presentation skills.
- Designed my E-Portfolio: fadyfaheem.com, and started projects on my GitHub: FadyFaheem
- Programmed and designed a Raspberry Pi Powered Vending Machine which was donated to St. Meena Orthodox Church. (Project listed on my website!)

Created and developed Unity Games in a 2D, 3D, and VR format with the latest technologies

Edikt Studios

Keller, TX

Unity Game Developer Intern

August 2019-Present

- Designed and soon to release a fully built Unity game from Edikt Studios on Steam.

EDUCATION

TIMBERCREEK HIGHSCHOOL

Fort Worth, TX

May 2023

Certification in Computer Science and Highschool Diploma, (GPA: 3.7/4.0)